اَعُوْذُ بِاللهِ مِنَّ الشِّيْطَانِ الرَّجِيْمِ۞
بِسْمِ اللهِ الرَّحْمَانِ الرَّحِيْمَ۞
اَلْحَمْدُ لله ، وَالصَّلَاةُ وَالسَّلَامُ عَلى سَيِّدِنَا محمد وَعَلَى اَلِهِ وَصَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ تَسْلِيْمًا كَثِيْرا
We'll move on to the next subject,
and we're going to talk about some of the glad tidings of the coming of Muhammadﷺ
the glad tidings that came before his Prophet hood.
This Hadith(حديث) which is mentioned by Ibn Is'haqq(اِبْنِ اِسْحَاقْ).
He says; the one who was stating this Hadith(حديث) is Salamah Bin Salam Bin Waqsh(سلمه بن سلام بن وقش).
He said: We had a Jewish neighbor from Bannu Abd-Al-Ash'hal(بنوعبدالأشهل),
and he came out of his house one day to us,
at that time, I was the youngest of my household.
I was wearing a fur gown,
a fur gown, I had that I was lying in it, in the courtyard of my family's house.
The Jew talked about the resurrection, the day of judgment, the reckoning, the scales, paradise and hellfire.
This he told to Polytheists idolaters, who did not believe in any life after death.
They replied, come on now, you really think people can be sent after their death,
to some place where there's a paradise and a fire,
where they will be punished for their deeds.
Yes, indeed, he replied.
And by Him, by Whom oaths are sworn.
Anyone going into that fire would prefer being placed in the hottest oven in the house,
and having it covered over him,
and he being let out of it only next day.
Then they said: "Good gracious, what proof is there?
They asked!
He said; A Prophet is being sent from the hereabouts, in these lands.
And he gestured over towards Makkah and Yemen.
When will we see him?
They inquired!
He looked over at me,
I being the youngest one there and he said
if this lad lives a normal lifespan
he'll live to this time.
Salamah(سلمه) said: And a day and a night had scarcely passed thereafter, until God send the Messenger of Allah, who lived among us,
and so we believed in him,
but he the Jew disbelieved in him out of evil and envy.
So, this Jewish man, who has studied, he learned from his books,
learned from the old scripture, that there is a Prophet, who will be sent from the direction of Makkah,
and that there is Hellfire and paradise
and he knew that the time was approaching and it was very near.
However, when the Prophet was sent, this man refused to follow him, out of envy.
And there are many narrations similar to this,
of Jews knowing that the time of Muhammadﷺ has approached.
In fact, the Jews who were in Madina as we mentioned were there because they were expecting the Prophet.
That's the whole reason behind them, settling in Madina.
And they used to tell the Arabs of Madina Al-Aos Wal Khazraj(اَلْاوس وَالْخزرج),
they used to tell them, whenever they would have the dispute, that one day there is going to be a Prophet sent among us,
and when that happens, we're going to kill you, like the people of Aad(عاد) were killed.
And Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله) that was preparation for Al-Aos Wal Khazraj(اَلْاوس وَالْخزرج),
because Al-Aos Wal Khazraj(اَلْاوس وَالْخزرج) use to hear this from the Jews,
they were aware, unlike the other Arabs, they were aware that the Prophet is coming.
So, when they met Muhammadﷺ in Makkah, they(أنصار) immediately believed
because they(أنصار) knew that this was the person
the Jews were talking about, in fact, what they(أنصار) said in that meeting
when they(أنصار) met with Rasool Allah ﷺ, on the first day, they(أنصار) went back to their tents and they(أنصار) said
this is the man the Jews have been threatening us with,
let's follow him first.
Let's be the first to follow him,
let's not let the Jews beat us to him.
So they were in fact, in a hurry to belief because they wanted to be the first.
But then Al-Yahood(أليهود) refused to follow Muhammadﷺ.
We'll talk about some of the glad tidings of Muhammadﷺ in the present day Bible.
Obviously, the Bible went through series of development and changes.
So, not all of the glad tidings that were there, exist but still, there is a sufficient number in the Bible,
that should be an indication to current day People of the Book, to follow the message of Muhammadﷺ.
There's a verse in Deuteronomy this verse 18:18,
this verse states I, God will raise them up a Prophet from among their brethren like unto thee Moses
and I'll put My words in his mouth and he shall speak unto them all that I shall command him.
Now this prophecy fits Muhammadﷺ like a glove.
Exactly.
And it fits no one else.
The verse starts by saying that I, God will raise them up a Prophet from among their brethren like unto thee, Moses.
So Allah is saying that Allah will send a Prophet who is like, Moses.
Now, who was the Prophet who resembled Moses the most.?
Now the Christians claim that this is talking about Jesus.
So, let's see who resembles Musa(موسى) more, Muhammadﷺ or Eesa(عيسى).
Number one: Moses had parents,
Muhammadﷺ had parents,
while Eesa(عيسى) had only a mother.
So, that's the first similarity between Musa(موسى) and Muhammad(محمد) which is not shared by Eesa(عيسى), Jesus عليه السّلام.
Number two:
Both Moses and Muhammadﷺ had children, while Jesus never had any children.
Number three:
Moses was born in a natural way,
Muhammadﷺ was born in a natural way,
while Eesa عليه السّلام was born in a miraculous fashion,
He was born without a father.
Number four: Musa(موسى) was accepted by his nation,
And Muhammadﷺ was accepted by his nation,
while Jesus was rejected by his nation.
So, that's another resemblance.
It says in the Bible, he, Jesus came on to his own, but his own received him not.
He was sent to the Jews and the Jews rejected him,
while Musa(موسى) was sent to the Jews and overall they accepted him
and Muhammadﷺ was sent to his people and they accepted him.
Number five:
Moses and Muhammadﷺ were kings or rulers, they were rulers on Earth,
while Eesa عليه السّلام was not
and when we say rulers
they had the power to inflict capital punishment.
We know in our Shariah(شريعه),
that only the Sultan(سلطان) can enforce Hadood(حدود)
right,
the Hadood(حدود), which is the capital punishment and the other forms of punishment, cannot be done by a scholar or any Muslim,
they have to be done by the Sultan(سلطان), by the leader, by the ruler.
Both Muhammadﷺ and Musa(موسى) had that power.
For example with Musa(موسى),
It says there's an incident when the Jews brought before Musa(موسى),
an Israelite, who had been caught collecting firewood on the Sabith(سابت).
So, Musa(موسى) had him stoned to death.
That's in numbers 15:36.
So, Musa(موسى) did stone a person to death.
And Muhammadﷺ did apply punishment,
when the woman came to him professing adultery.
But with Eesa عليه السّلام, when they brought him, a case of a crime.
He refused to inflict punishment and he said:
My kingdom is not of this world,
My kingdom is not of this world, I'm not the ruler here.
And this is in John 18:36.
So, now we have pointed out five similarities.
Number six:
Muhammadﷺ came with a new law, the law of Qur'an.
Musa عليه السّلام came with a new law, and that's the law of the Tauraah(توراة).
While Eesa عليه السّلام, Jesus came to follow the law of Musa عليه السّلام.
He says in one verse, "I came to follow the law, jot by jot, dot by dot, letter by letter.
And he also said in Matthew five, verse 17, and 18.
Think not that I am come to destroy the law or the Prophets,
I am not come to destroy  but to fulfill.
For verily I say unto you, till heaven and earth pass, one jot or one title, shall in no wise pass from the law till all be fulfilled.
I came to fulfill the law of Musa عليه السّلام.
So, these are six points of similarity.
Number seven:
I mean Subhaan Allah(سُبْحَان الله), the resemblance between Muhammadﷺ and Musa(موسى) is striking.
Musa(موسى) has led his people in Hijrah(هجرة),
in a mass exodus out of Egypt to the Holy Land,
Muhammadﷺ has led his people in Hijrah(هجرة)
while Eesa عليه السّلام has never left his land and never made Hijrah(هجرة).
And one of the most important events to us Muslims in the history of Rasool Allah ﷺ was Hijrah(هجرة).
And that's why it's the beginning of our calendar.
That's where we start counting history from.
So, it's a very important event and to the Jews,
the Hijrah(هجرة) of Banni Israel(بني إسرائيل) out of Egypt is a very important event to them.
In fact, many of their celebrations are based on that event.
So, this is a very important point of similarity between Muhammadﷺ and Musa(موسى).
Number seven:
Both Musa عليه السّلام and Muhammadﷺ were victorious against their enemies,
Moses won against Firaun(فرعون), and Muhammadﷺ won against the ones, who fought him,
while Eesa(عيسى) has never won in the worldly sense.
He has never won in a battle in this world.
In fact, the Christians believed that he was killed,
this is not a belief that we share with them, but this is where they stand.
So, that's point number eight,
Number nine
Musa عليه السّلام died a natural death,
Muhammadﷺ died a natural death,
the Christians believe that Jesus, he was killed,
while the Muslims believe that he was elevated, so either way it was not a natural death.
Number 10:
Both Musa عليه السّلام and Muhammadﷺ are buried in the ground,
while the Christians believe Jesus was buried and then resurrected,
while the Muslims believe he was never buried to start with.
Number 11:
Which is a similarity that we could bring up according to the Christian belief.
Most Christians claim that Jesus is God.
And the reason why could we could use this as an evidence is, because they are the ones who are claiming that Jesus is similar to Moses,
so we can bring up the point, how do you believe that He is God,
and then you say that he is similar to Musa(موسى), who was a Prophet
while the Muslims say that Muhammadﷺ was a Prophet.
Resemblance between them now we're at number 12.
When did Muhammadﷺ become a Prophet.?
At the age of 40.
When did Musa عليه السّلام become a Prophet?
And that stated in the Bible,
and the Bible states that Eesa(عيسى), Jesus peace be upon him became a prophet at the age of 30.
So, Muhammadﷺ and Musa(موسى) were given Prophet hood at the same age,
while Eesa عليه السّلام was given Prophet hood at a younger age.
Point Number 13:
Christians claim that Jesus was resurrected after his death.
Neither Muslims nor Christians claim that Musa(موسى) or Muhammadﷺ was resurrected.
Therefore, Muhammadﷺ is like Moses, but Jesus is unlike Moses.
And we can go on with some further points, I think the important is made,
that the person, who most resembled Moses عليه السّلام is Muhammadﷺ.
No one came after Musa عليه السّلام who resembled him, like Muhammadﷺ, by all standards.
Now we talked about the similarity between this Prophet and Moses, like unto thee.
So, let's look at other aspects of the prophecy.
Now, since we have determined that Eesa Ibn Maryam(عيسى إبن مريم) this prophecy does not apply to him,
so who does it apply to then?
Could it be someone else from among the Jews?
Since Musa(موسى) is giving a prophecy and he is speaking to the Jews.
Could it be someone other than Jesus?
Well, he cannot be a Jew!
The person whom this prophecy is talking about cannot be a Jew.
Because it says in Deuteronomy 34:10
And there arose not a prophet since in Israel(اسرائيل) like unto Moses.
So, this statement, makes it clear that there would be no one among,
Banni Israel(بني إسرائيل) the children of Israel(اسرائيل), who is similar to Moses
again, and there arose not a prophet since in Israel(اسرائيل) like unto Moses.
so none, none of the prophets of Banni Israel(بني إسرائيل) is comparable to Moses.
So, who is it then?
Well, the answer is right there, in the prophecy.
It says: "Prophet from among their brethren."
So, in the prophecy, it's also excludes the Jews, it says from among their brethren, the brethren of the Jews.
So, here we have a Prophet from among the brethren of the Jews.
And who are the brethrens of the Jews?
Actually, there's only one nation that fulfills this description.
And that is, The Arabs.
Why.?
Because Ibrahim عليه السّلام had two sons and two sons only
Is'haaq(اِسْحَاق) and Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل).
Is'haaq(اِسْحَاق) is the father of the Jews, Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل) is the father of the Arabs.
Is'haaq(اسحاق) had Yaqoob(يعقوب)
and Yaqoob(يعقوب) is the father of the 12 tribes.
So, the Jews trace their ancestry to Is'haq(اسحاق),
while the Arabs trace their ancestry to Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل).
So, this verses are very clear
I mean, it says; that here you have a prophet like Moses,
and we saw the similarities between Muhammadﷺ and Moses
and he is not a Jew, but he is from among the brethren of the Jews, which are the Arabs.
And then the prophecy goes on to say,
and "will put My words in his mouth.
So, God is saying that I will put My words in his mouth.
In other words, this prophet will not be speaking of his own,
but he will be speaking the words which are put in his mouth.
And again, this fits exactly on the situation of Muhammadﷺ,
Allah سبحانه وتعالى says,
وَمَا يَنْطِقُ عَنِ الْهَوَىٰ۝
Muhammad(محمد) is not speaking from his own,
He's not speaking from his own desires, he's speaking the words that are put in his mouth by Allah سبحانه وتعالى.
So, Jibreel(جِبْرِيْل) is putting the words of Allah in the mouth of Muhammadﷺ.
And you have in Qur'an many versus Allah سبحانه وتعالى is speaking,
I am your Lord
أَنَا اللَّهُ لَا إِلَٰهَ إِلَّا أَنَا، أنا ربكم
I am your Lord, I am your God and other verses and the Qur'an.
All of Qur'an is the words of Allah سبحانه وتعالى put in the mouth of Muhammadﷺ.
Now, the Bible is different
Christians claim that the Bible was inspired by God,
but the words are the words of men.
And they admit that the Bible has many authors
many different authors,
and the chapters of the Bible or the books of the Bible are named after these authors.
So, you have John, you have Matthew, you have Luke.
So, these are the names of the authors of these books.
Dr. Graham's Scroggie of the Moody Bible Institute.
He says in his book,
It is Human, Yet Divine".
He says,
Yes, the Bible is human
although some out of zeal which is not according to knowledge, have denied this.
Those books have been passed through the minds of men
are written in the language of men,
were penned by the hands of men,
and bear in their style, the characteristics of men.
Qur'an is different,
Qur'an is by Allah.
And Muhammadﷺ was only the one, who was speaking it.
But it is the words of Allahعَزّوجَلّ put in his mouth.
The final part of the prophecy states that
and he shall speak unto them all that I shall command him.
Meaning, he will not withhold any information,
everything that he is given, He will speak it
and Allah سبحانه وتعالى says in Qur'an,
يَا أَيُّهَا الرَّسُولُ بَلِّغْ مَا أُنْزِلَ إِلَيْكَ مِنْ رَبِّكَ ۖ
وَإِنْ لَمْ تَفْعَلْ فَمَا بَلَّغْتَ رِسَالَتَهُ ۚ
وَاللَّهُ يَعْصِمُكَ مِنَ النَّاسِ ۗ
إِنَّ اللَّهَ لَا يَهْدِي الْقَوْمَ الْكَافِرِينَ۝
Allah سبحانه وتعالى is telling Muhammadﷺ,
O Prophet of Allah! Convey everything that you have received
and if you don't do so, then you have not conveyed the message.
Meaning if you only withhold one word that was given to you, you have not fulfilled your role.
You have not fulfilled your responsibility.
So, everything that Muhammadﷺ received, he delivered it.
Even, when it was verses of Qur'an criticizing an action of his,
like for example in Surah Al-Abas(سورة العبس),
when Rasool Allah ﷺ was speaking to the noble man from Quraish(قُرَيْشْ)
and he ignored the blind man, Ibn Al-Maktoom(إبن ألمكتوم), Allah سبحانه وتعالى said,
عَبَسَ وَتَوَلَّىٰ َ أَنْ جَاءَهُ الْأَعْمَىٰ۝
Words that are criticizing that action of Muhammadﷺ
and similar can be said about verses of Surah Al-Tahreem(سورة التحريم).
يَا أَيُّهَا النَّبِيُّ لِمَ تُحَرِّمُ مَا أَحَلَّ اللَّهُ لَكَ ۖ
تَبْتَغِي مَرْضَاتَ أَزْوَاجِكَ ۚ
وَاللَّهُ غَفُورٌ رَحِيمٌ۝
O Messenger of Allah, Why are you making what is Halal(حلال), haram(حرام) on yourself in order to please your wives,
and what can go on another examples.
So, Rasool Allah ﷺ conveyed everything that was given to him.
So that's one prophecy.
We have another prophecy in Isaiah 29, verses 11 to 18
I'm not going to read the whole thing, I'm going to read part of it.
And you determine what this is talking about, it's quite obvious, straight forward.
It doesn't need any interpretation or explanation.
It says,
and the book is delivered to him that is not learned
saying, read this.
And he says, I am not learned.
Quite obvious, the book is delivered to a man, who was unlettered, illiterate
And he is told read,
And he responds back by saying I cannot read.
These are the exact words that were given by Jibreelعليه السّلام to Muhammad ﷺ
in his first encounter with Wahii(وحي), with revelation.
And we're going to notice here that the Bible is talking about the major events
pretty much all of the major events that happened in the life of Muhammadﷺ, are in the Bible.
You have the first revelation,
you have Hijrah(هجرة), you have Ghazwa Al Badr(غزوة البدر),
it talks about Fateh Makkah(فتح مكه)
These are the major events in the life of Muhammadﷺ and they're all in the Bible.
Now again, the verse is and the book is delivered to him that is not learned, saying read this, I pray thee,
and he says; I am not learned.
Now the first verses revealed in Qur'an were,
اِقْرَأْ بِاسْمِ رَبِّكَ الَّذِي خَلَقَ۝ خَلَقَ الْإِنْسَانَ مِنْ عَلَقٍ۝
اقْرَأْ وَرَبُّكَ الْأَكْرَمُ۝ الَّذِي عَلَّمَ بِالْقَلَمِ۝ عَلَّمَ الْإِنْسَانَ مَا لَمْ يَعْلَمْ۝
Read in the name of Your Lord, Who created,
created man from clot,
read,
and Your Lord is the Most bounteous, Who teaches by the pen, teaches man that which he knew not.
What is even more interesting?
If we would go back to the original, which is in Hebrew, the word read is Qara.
So, if one would go back to the original Hebrew, it is the exact same word as Arabic
Qara.
And it is spelled in English the way it was in this book q, a, r, a
and it is pronounced قَارَاؤ
The author of the book says is it not an amazing coincidence that the Hebrew text us not only a word with the same meaning,
but the exact same word itself.
The prophecy continues and it states that
before the time of this man, who will receive the book, Muhammadﷺ,
it says that the people would be forsaking the words of God for the precept of men.
So, it states that before the time of Muhammadﷺ people would neglect the law of Allah,
and they would follow the law of man.
And this is exactly what happened
Jesus peace be upon him came to fulfill the law of Moses.
And then you have Saint Paul coming in, and telling them otherwise.
So, Jesus was circumcised.
Paul says, No, you don't have to circumcise.
Jesus said, I came to fulfill the law, letter by letter, jot by jot, word by word.
Paul said, No, you do not have to fulfill the law.
So, they left the law of God and they follow the law of man, which is a fulfillment of this prophecy.
I could recite the whole prophecy it says:
And the vision of all is become unto you, as the words of a book that is sealed.
So, there's a sealed book, which men delivered to one that is learned saying read this
And he says, I cannot for it is sealed.
So, Qur'an was sealed.
And even the learned men did not have access to it before Muhammadﷺ
because it was destined to go to the man, who was unlearned.
And the book is delivered to him that is not learned saying read this.
And he says I am not learned.
Therefore The Lord said: For as much as this people draw near me with their mouth
and with their lips do honor me, but have removed their heart far from me,
and their fear toward me is taught by the precept of men.
So now, the people are following the words of men.
The Hijrah(هجرة) is mentioned, is prophesized in Habakkuk 3, verse 3
it says "God, His guidance came from the Teemaan(تيمان)
and the holy one from Mount Paraan.
Selah, His glory covered the heavens and the earth was full of his praise.
So, it says his glory covered the heavens and the earth was full of his praise.
It mentions two locations, Teemaan and Paraan.
Teemaan is according to the Jay Hasting's Dictionary of the Bible,
Teemaan is an oasis, just north of Madina.
So, Teemaan stands for Madina,
teemaa, Teemaan will stand for Madina.
It's a locality just north of Madina.
Where is Paraan?
Paraan or Faraan are Makkah.
These are names of Makkah,
and that is according to the Bible because the Bible states that Hajar(هَاجَر) and Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل) were left in Paraan.
And obviously we know where Hajar(هَاجَر) and Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل) were left.
They were left in Makkah.
So, the name Faraan or Paraan or Bakkah(بكة) are all different names of Makkah(مكة).
So, you have God coming from Teemaan, which is Madina.
And you have the Holy One, from Mount Paraan.
Where did Islam spread from?
Islam spread from Madina, it did not spread from Makkah.
When Rasool Allah ﷺ was making Da'wah(دعوة) in Makkah, Islam was contained,
the message was not spreading.
The number of people who adopted it were very few.
And Rasool Allah ﷺ left Makkah because of the restrictions placed on him
because he was not allowed to preach the message.
So, the religion of Islam spread from Madina.
That is when Islam went all over the world.
So, God came from Teemaan, meaning the guidance of Allah came from Madina.
But then the verse goes on to say, the holy one, came from Paraan.
So, the Holy one which is Muhammadﷺ came from Makkah.
And then it states that his glory covered the heavens
and the earth was full of his praise.
And Muhammadﷺ, his name means praise,
and the earth today is full of his praise,
and this cannot fit anyone more than Muhammadﷺ because there is not a single person in history,
who is praised more than Muhammadﷺ.
So, this prophecy fits the Hijrah(هجرة) exactly Muhammadﷺ making Hijrah(هجرة) from Makkah to Madina,
his religion spreading from Madina and the world is full of the praise of Muhammad صلوات الله وسلام عليه.
In Deutronomy 18, 21 to 22.
And if thou say in thine heart
how shall we know the word which the Lord has not spoken.
So, here the Bible is telling us the acid test to know
whether a man is speaking on behalf of God or not?
How can we distinguish a liar from somebody who's telling the truth?
It goes on to say, when a prophet speaks in the name of the Lord,
if the thing follow not, nor come to pass
that is the thing which the Lord has not spoken.
But the Prophet has spoken it presumptuously, Thou shall not be afraid of him.
If a prophet says something, and claims that this is coming from Allah, and it does not come to happen
then those words are not spoken by the prophet.
Therefore everything a prophet says, will come to happen, will come to pass.
Qur'an, which is the words of Allah سبحانه وتعالى given to Muhammadﷺ,
is proving to us every day, new miracles, scientific miracles, showing the truth of Al-Qur'an.
Now, there might have been scientific verses in other books that preceded Qur'an that came to happen.
But you would also find in those books mistakes,
because they are written by men.
With Qur'an everything that it mentioned was proven to be true,
and there are no contradictions in it and nothing in Qur'an was proved to be false.
So, not only did Qur'an prophesized about things that will happen in the future.
But Qur'an does not contain any errors in it.
Because, for example out of pure coincidence and probability,
a man 2000 years ago can go ahead and write predictions about the future,
one could occur to be true, and then 10 false.
So, we can't go and say, Well, this man is receiving this information from God
because it has one single thing that was mentioned in it, talking about the future.
For it to be from God than everything in it needs to be true.
And that holds true to no book other than Al-Qur'an
There is nothing in the Qur'an that has been disproved.
And that will never happen and Allah سبحانه وتعالى has challenged the people in Qur'an
to produce anything similar to it and the challenges is still open
and nobody has been able to face the challenge of Allah in Qur'an.
The challenge started by producing a book similar to it,
and then it was reduced to 10 Surah(سورة), chapters, and then finally one chapter.
Now the challenge is to produce one chapter, similar to Qur'an
In Isaiah 21:7, he saw a vision
and he saw a chariot with a couple of horsemen,
a chariot of asses, and the chariot of camels.
Christians would say that the chariot of asses is Eesa عليه السّلام
because he was the one, who would ride a donkey.
Who was the prophet who would ride a camel?
Is there any other prophet, who was known to ride a camel other than Muhammadﷺ.?
So, this is a prophecy that is speaking about Jesus عليه السّلام and Muhammadﷺ.
Now, it continues to say, in 29:9.
And behold, here comes a chariot of men, with a couple of horsemen,
and he answered and said, Babylon is fallen, is fallen.
And all the graven images of her gods, he has broken un to the ground.
Where is Babylon?
in present day, Iraq, Babylon is in Iraq.
The prophecy is saying that this army will destroy all of the false gods of Babylon
and will erase all of the images there in,
which army is that?
Who is this army?
whose army is it, that would go into Iraq
and eliminate all of the idol worshipping and erase all of the images,
of idolatry that existed in Iraq?
The only army that would fit this description
is the army that was sent by Umar Ibn Al-Khattab(عمر ابن الخطاب) to Iraq
and they have succeeded in opening Iraq and eliminating all of the false gods that existed there in,
so this is another prophecy that has been fulfilled.
Hijrah(هجرة) in Isaiah 21, verse 14, and 15, another reference to Hijrah(هجرة).
The inhabitants of the land of Taemaah
brought water to him that was thirsty
they prevented with their bread him that fled,
for they fled from the swords from the drawn sword,
and from the bent bow and from the greviousness of war.
So, Muhammadﷺ made Hijrah(هجرة) and the Ansaar(أنْصَار) supported him with their bread.
So, this is also talking about Hijrah(هجرة), and Al-Ansaar(أنْصَار)
In Isaiah 21, verses 16 to 17
For thus has the Lord said unto me
within a year, according to the years of a hireling
and all the glory of Kedar shall fail
and the residue of the member of archers, the mighty men, of the children of Kedar, it's actually Qidaar
shall be diminished for the Lord, God of Israel(اسرائيل) has spoken it.
Who is Qidaar?
or an English Kadar, who is that referring to  k, e, d, a, r,
Well, let's Let the Bible Speak for itself.
It states in Genesis 25:13.
And these are the names of the sons of Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل), by their names according to their generations
the first born of Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل), Nabachos, and Kedar and Adbeel and Mibsaam.
So, Kedar is one of the sons of Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل).
In the Bible, when it talks about the princes of Kedar, it is referring to the Arabs.
Qidaar in Arabic it is Qidaar,
and the people of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) are descendants of Qidaar.
Let's go back to the prophecy again
For thus has the Lord said unto me, within year
according to the years of a hireling
and all the glory of Kedar shall fail.
And the residue of the number of archers, the mighty men of the children of Kedar shall be diminished
for the Lord, God of Israel(اسرائيل) has spoken it."
What is this referring to.
We just spoke about Hijrah(هجرة).
Right!
In verse 1415.
We spoke about Hijrah(هجرة) and how the Ansaar(أنْصَار) helped Rasool Allah ﷺ.
Now we are in verse 16 and 17
What is the event that happened one year after Hijrah(هجرة)
and notice here that it says that the glory of Kedar shall fail,
Quraish(قُرَيْشْ).
And the residue of the number of archers, the mighty men of the children of Kedar shall be diminished,
they will be killed.
What is this reffering to.?
The Battle of Badr(بدر)
and the Battle of Badr(بدر) occurred in the second year of Hijrah(هجرة),
one year after the Hijrah(هجرة) of Rasool Allah ﷺ.
So, this is referring to the Battle of Badr(بدر).
And it says that the mighty men of the children of Kedar shall be diminished.
In the battle of Badr, one of the most decisive battles in the history of Islam, all of the leaders of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ) were killed.
The leaders of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), who were the most brutal in their war against Islam, were eliminated,
Abu Jahal(ابو جهل)
Umayya Bin Khalaf(اميه بن خلف),
Uqba Bin Abi Moayet(عقبه بن ابي معيت)
and down the list, one could go naming all of the names of the non believers of Quraish(قُرَيْشْ), who died during the Battle of Badr.
In Isaiah 11 verses one and two.
And they shall come forth a rod out of the stem of Jesse,
and a branch shall grow out of his roots,
and the Spirit of the Lord shall rest upon him.
The spirit of wisdom and understanding,
the spirit of counsel and might,
the spirit of knowledge and of the fear of the Lord.
Who is Jesse.?
According to the encyclopedia biblica,
Jesse for Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل), Ijmael, so Jesse is a contraction of Ijmael.
And then it goes on to say the changes which proper names undergo in the mouth of small children
account for a large number of these particular abbreviations.
Who could guess to take modern examples
that Bob and Dick arose out of Robert and Richard.
Such forms, as in, they were particularly common in later times
and in many more in Talmood, which also exhibits various other kinds of abbreviation.
So you have Bob standing for Robert
wonder how small children would make that drastic change.
But anyway, Jesse stands for Ijmael, Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل).
So now, that we know that Jesse is Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل).
Let's revisit the verse,
And there shall come forth a rod out of the stem of jesse,
meaning from the descendants of Ismail(اِسْماعِيْل)
and a branch shall grow out of his roots.
And the Spirit of the Lord shall rest upon him.
The spirit of wisdom and understanding, the spirit of counsel and might, the spirit of knowledge and of the fear of the Lord.
Now this prophecy cannot fit on anyone except Muhammadﷺ
because he was the most prominent descendant of Ismail عليه السّلام
Deuteronomy, 33, 1:
And this is the blessing, where with Moses, the man of God blessed the children of Israel(اسرائيل) before his death,
and he said
the Lord came from Sinai
and rose up from Seir unto them,
he shined forth from Mount Paraan
And he came with 10 thousands of saints from his right hand went a fiery law for them.
So, now Musa(موسى) is speaking to the children of Israel(اسرائيل) before his death.
He's giving them a prophecy.
He's saying, the Lord came from Sinai, Sinaa(سيناء)
rose up from Seir unto them
he shined forth from Mount Paraan.
Sina(سيناء) is where the message of Musa(موسى) came from.
So, this is referring to himself, Sina(سيناء).
Saeeir in Arabic or SEIR in English seir, stands for Eesa(عيسى),
the message of Eesa(عيسى) because that is a series of mountains in Falasteen(فلسطين),
close to where Eesa(عيسى) Jesus, peace be upon him lived
so that is referring to Eesa عليه السّلام.
Mount Paraan again is Makkah.
So, it's talking about Muhammadﷺ, and this is similar to what was mentioned in Surah At-Tein(سورة التين).
وَالتِّينِ وَالزَّيْتُونِ۝ وَطُورِ سِينِينَ۝
At-Tein(ألتين) is figs,
and Figs is associated with Falasteen(فلسطين).
They grow a lot of figs.
And then you have,
وَالتِّينِ وَالزَّيْتُونِ۝
And also Zaitoon(زيتون), olives, so these are referring to Musa(موسى) and Eesa(عيسى)
وَطُورِ سِينِينَ۝
Is referring to the message of same thing Eesa(عيسى) and Musa عليه السّلام
وَهَٰذَا الْبَلَدِ الْأَمِينِ۝
Makkah.
So, it's pretty similar thing in Surah(سورة) At-Tein(سورة التين)
But with this prophecy here, Musa عليه السّلام is talking about his message,
that's a beginning of the Da'wah(دعوة)
and then Eesaعليه السّلام will carry it further,
but then it will rise from Paraan,
meaning the fulfillment of the message will come from Makkah.
It goes on to say, and he came with 10,000 saints.
Who are the 10,000 saints?
Sahabah رضي الله عنهم when they opened Makkah, Mout Paraan
Fath Makkah(فتح مكه) was done by 10,000.
Rasool Allah ﷺ had 10,000 men with him when they opened Makkah.
And from his right hand went a fiery law for them.
And the right hand stands for truth, justice and strength.
The Paraclete also stands for Muhammadﷺ, there's a few verses in which this was mentioned.
It's also sometimes translated as the comforter.
In john 16, verses 7 to 14 it states
Nevertheless, I tell you the truth
it is expedient for you that I go away
For if I go not away, the Comforter will not come unto you,
but if I depart, I will send him on to you.
And when he is come he will reprove the world of sin
and of righteousness and of judgment
of sin, because they believe not on me
of righteousness because I go to my father, and you see me no more
of judgment, because the prince of this world is judged.
I have yet many things to say unto you,
but you cannot bear them now.
How Be it, when he, The Spirit of Truth is come, he will guide you into all truth.
For he shall not speak of himself,
but whatsoever he shall hear that shall he speak
and he will shew you things to come.
He shall glorify Me, for he shall receive of Mine and he shall shew it unto you.
I'm not going to go into explaining all of this but I think the meaning is clear that this is referring to Muhammadﷺ.
So, these are some of the prophecies mentioned about Muhammadﷺ,
in the Bible and some other events that happened during his mission.
We're done with the Pre-Prophet hood era.
And now in sha Allah Ta'ala(اِن شَا الله تعالى), we can start with the Prophet hood.
صَلَّى الله عَلى سَيَّدِنَا محمد وَعَلى اَلِهِ وَ صَحْبِهِ وَسَلِّمْ تَسْلِيْمًا كَثِيْرًا